<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>reviews on AW - notes &amp; thoughts</title>
    <link>https://coffepowered.github.io/categories/reviews/</link>
    <description>Recent content in reviews on AW - notes &amp; thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 21:28:43 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://coffepowered.github.io/categories/reviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sparse notes</title>
      <link>https://coffepowered.github.io/blogs/2022-sparse-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 21:28:43 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://coffepowered.github.io/blogs/2022-sparse-notes/</guid>
      <description>Data science march Effect of irrelevant features - a nice experimental test march Matrix factorizaton recap in 6minutes march mean encodings: a comprehesive study, check also category_encoders sklearn library march relationship between SVD and PCA + a comprehensive tutorial on arxiv march Naive-Bayes classification from scratch On Embeddings for Numerical Features in Tabular Deep Learning Euclidean vs cosine distance Data viz Complimentary Temporary Staging area for links that will be forgotten soon:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Q1 2023: Miscellanea (playlist)</title>
      <link>https://coffepowered.github.io/blogs/q1-2023-podcasts-and-readings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 21:28:43 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://coffepowered.github.io/blogs/q1-2023-podcasts-and-readings/</guid>
      <description>Usare i numeri ciecamente: la fallacia di McNamara Due note brevi sulla fallacia di McNamara (segretario della difesa USA durante la guerra in Vietnam), spesso riassunta come &amp;ldquo;fallacia quantitativa&amp;rdquo;&#xA;“the facts which count best count most&amp;quot;. [I fatti che si contano meglio sono quelli che contano di più]&#xA;Spesso è figlia delle organizzazioni, ma colpisce (duro) individui e decisioni. Come fare a riprodurla? Ecco un tutorial (preso da qui):&#xA;As reported by Smith, Yankelovich describes the fallacy as follows:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The economics of the agri-food value chain</title>
      <link>https://coffepowered.github.io/blogs/economics-agri-food-value-chain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 21:28:43 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://coffepowered.github.io/blogs/economics-agri-food-value-chain/</guid>
      <description>Course review Let me paraphrase what Tukey once said: I truly believe that getting in contact with different fields and expertise is one of the perks of being a data scientist. Pictorially:&#xA;The best thing about being a statistician data scientist, Mr Tukey once told a colleague, is that you get to play in everyone&amp;rsquo;s backyard.&#xA;So, even if you can legitimately play in everyone&amp;rsquo;s backyard - which oftentimes means cleaning it as a first step, it also means that you will be speaking to people with different backgrounds ad expertise.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
